Now, let's take a different example.
لنأخذ الآن مثالًا مختلفًا.
I was working as a freelance consultant on
وقتما كنت أعمل استشاريًا حرًا على
a development project for a client in the Southeast in the US.
مشروع تنموي لعميل في الجنوب الشرقي من الولايات المتحدة.
I noticed that the client was using the Amazon Cloud to host their application,
لاحظت أن العميل يستخدم سحابة Amazon لاستضافة التطبيق الخاص به،
and they were paying $500 per month for the hosting.
وكان يدفع 500 دولار شهريًا مقابل تلك الاستضافة.
Now, a simple web app with 500 users doesn't have much infrastructure cost these days,
في حين لا تكلف البنية التحتية لتطبيق شبكي بسيط له أكثر من 500 مستخدم الكثير هذه الأيام
especially on the Cloud.
خاصة على السحابة.
I noticed that they were using a lot of servers on
لاحظت أن العميل كان يستخدم الكثير من الخوادم
the Cloud that they won't need unless they reach a critical mass of the users,
السحابة والتي لم يكن ليحتاجها إلا عند وصوله لحجم هائل من المستخدمين
maybe like 300,000 users.
لـ300,000 مستخدم مثلًا.
Unless they reach 300,000 users,
فطالما هو لم يبلغ 300,000 مستخدم
they won't need so many servers.
فهو لا يحتاج إلى كل تلك الخوادم.
Something like that doesn't have enough value for me to
شيء من هذا القبيل ليس له قيمة كافية بالنسبة لي
fix personally in terms of revenue from the client.
حتى أصلحه بنفسي من حيث العائد الذي سوف يعود علي من العميل.
I just need to get on one call and try to explain it to
وكل ما احتاجه هو مكالمة واحدة أحاول فيها شرح الأمر
the client and they'll take care of the rest in case they're convinced.
للعميل ثم أتركه بعد ذلك يتولى الأمر في حالة اقتناعه به.
But it would be of immense value to the client if that is fixed.
ولكن كان الأمر ليكون ذا قيمة كبيرة جدًا للعميل إذا تم إصلاحه.
I made the effort to do that and the client was able to reduce their costs by
ولهذا بذلت الجهد لأفعل هذا واستطاع العميل تخفيض تكاليفه
90 percent of what they were paying earlier to the Amazon Cloud.
بنسبة 90 بالمائة مما كان يدفعه سابقًا لسحابة Amazon.
Even though this was not of significant value to me in terms of revenue,
حتى وإن لم يعن هذا الأمر لي الكثير من حيث العائد
this deepened clients' trust in me,
إلا أنه عمق ثقة العميل بي
causing them to continue to give work to me at a rate that I was comfortable with.
وجعله يستمر في تكليفي بالأعمال بمعدل مريح بالنسبة لي.